## CURRICULUM VITAE

Sunday, Oct. 11, 2020



## EDUCATION

#### **Bachelor in Computer Engineering**

Pulchowk Campus, IOE, Tribhuvan University

2012 - 2016

Aggregate Score: 70.56% (First Division)

#### +2 Science

SOS Hermann Gmeiner HSS, HSEB

2010 - 2012

Aggregate Score: 79.20% (Distinction)

## SKILLS

 $\textbf{Programming Languages:} \ \mathsf{Python},$ 

JavaScript, C, C++

Web Frameworks: Django, Django Rest

Framework

Frontend: ReactJS, React Native, jQuery,

HTML, CSS

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Sqlite

Server: AWS, Digital Ocean

Data Science: Matlab, Octave, Numpy

Other: Docker, GraphQL, Bash

# **ANISH SHRESTHA**

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Phone: (977) 9860 140468 | Email: anish.shrestha5432@gmail.com Address: Madhyapur Thimi, Bhaktapur, Nepal, 44811 | Web: annshress.github.io

## ABOUT ME

I'm a 26 years old full stack developer currently based in Nepal. I am keen about everything that has to do with Python, Web design & development and Data Science. I feel a true devotion to become a Python Wizard. I am able to work independently as well as in teams.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

JUL 2020 - ongoing

#### Developer | Kathmandu

Togglecorp Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Kathmandu - Nepal

With Agile and Scrum methodologies, I am currently collaborating in developing web based tools to ease humanitarian relief works.

JAN 2020 - APR 2020

## Full Stack Developer | Remote

Freelance

I am active in Upwork and Fiverr. I built an improved CRM that reduced administration communication costs and improved customer information retrieval.

OCT 2018 - DEC 2019

## Full Stack Developer | Remote

Unified Private Limited, Florida, US

I collaboratively built a B2C application called Workplace. With TDD and Agile methodologies, we curtailed business weight of joining incongruous domain applications by pre-assembling them, while ensuring efficient individual and bulk profit analysis.

OCT 2016 - JAN 2019

## Software Developer | Kathmandu

Infiniahub Private Limited, Kathmandu, Nepal

As a Juvenile, I learned the most here. I created InfiniaStores for small-medium businesses where central agent can have complete control over several branches while reducing the overhead of order management and providing expense analysis. I increased Test Coverage by 30% for InfiniaBiz to increase resiliency of real-time communication between buying and selling agents.

## CERTIFICATES

## **GIS and Remote Sensing**

Resource Himalaya Foundation, Sanepa

## **Volunteering and Participation**

LOCUS (National Technological Fest)

## Stipend based on Merit

Institute of Engineering

## MEMBERSHIP

Nepal Engineering Council

## EXTRA COURSES

## **Introduction to Deep Learning**

Instructors: Alexender Panin et al., NRU Higher School of Economics, Coursera

#### **Machine Learning Instructors:**

Andrew Ng, Stanford University, Coursera

## **Computational Methods for Data Analysis Instructors:**

Andrew Nathan Kutz, University of Washington, Coursera

## PROJECTS

## Automated Facial Expression Analysis and Recognition (Major)

Using publicly available datasets like JAFFE, we applied Principal Component Analysis and Local Binary Patterns like feature extractors with Gabor Filters to feed into Support Vector Machine and Convolutional Neural Network classifiers. We were able to yield analytical and comparative study between applied methods.

## Football Result Predictor (Minor)

We successfully executed our first Machine Learning project to produce a comparative analysis on techniques like Back Propagation Neural Network, KNN, Naive Bayes to predict results of games of English Premier League based on past results.